Guide to the Buildings and Grounds collection A1000
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
Buildings and Grounds collection
1834-2007
A1000
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
24.3 Cubic feet
Colgate University. Buildings and Grounds.
Access to Collection
Collection is open for research.
Colgate University--Buildings.; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Negatives (photographic); Photographs.
- Andrews Hall
  - Postcard and small photos, Andrews Hall, undated; 8 items (Box 1)
  - Stone Negatives, Andrews Hall, undated; 13 items (Box 1)
  - Photos, Black and White, Andrews Hall (Exterior), circa 1944-1968; 9 items (Box 1)
  - Photos, Black and White, Andrews Hall (Interior), 1935; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Negatives, Andrews Hall, 1950-1969; 10 items (Box 1)
  - Snow mantles, Andrews Hall, undated; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Winter scene, Andrews Hall, circa 1944-1968; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Correspondence regarding Construction of Dormitory, Andrews Hall, 1921-1923; 46 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and legal arbitration, Andrews Hall, 1923-1926; 83 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Andrews Hall Construction, Accounts and Receipts, 1922-1926; 82 items (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gouge & Ames Architects, Specification for Dormitory, undated; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Alumni Hall
  Biographical/Historical note
  Built between 1859 and 1861, Alumni Hall is one of the three oldest buildings on the original campus. Alumni Hall originally housed the Chapel until the present Chapel was completed in 1918, and then the space was converted into classroom space. In 1965 a $600,000 renovation project was underway to modernize the interior.
  - Small Images, Alumni Hall and interior chapel, 1907, 1915, undated; 6 items (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cornerstones and plaques, 1953, 1965; 16 items (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Exterior views, undated; 12 items (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Before renovation, undated; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reconstruction, 1965; 49 items (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Post-Renovation, 1965, 1968, 1973, 1970; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Broussard, Phoenix and Meggett Negatives, 1965-1971; 20 items (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Exterior Photos mounted on cardboard, 1892, 1900, 1932, undated; 6 items (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dedication and laying of cornerstone, 1859-1861, 1888; 8 items (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Receipts and proposals regarding the building of Hall of Alumni & Friends, 1859-1861; 61 items (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Contracts- Heating, piping and drainage systems, 1910 May; 16 items (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Hall fire escape, 1931 November; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Development office, reconstruction of Alumni Hall, 1952, 1965; 3 items (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Specifications and building plans, 1964-1967; 32 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Interior photos and 35 mm slides, 1965; 7 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Proposed plaque, Alumni Hall, 1977 April 8; 2 items (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Athletic Fields and Buildings
  - Map of Athletic Fields, 1938; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Goalposts on Whitnall Field [Stone Y-23], undated; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Campus gate with old baseball field [Stone X-3], circa 1920; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Old Gym [Stone Y-88], undated; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Old baseball field [Stone Y-6], undated; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Whitnall Field, undated; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Field with puddle, undated; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Package of negatives. Football Stadium, undated; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Reid Athletic Center, 1965 September 2; 1 item (Box 5)
- Boarding Hall
  - Insurance Policies, 1882, 1885; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newsclipping,New York Evening Post, 1921 October 29; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "The Old Hall in Ashes,"Examiner and Chronicle, 1879 May 8; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Bunche House
  - 4 photographs, undated; 4 items (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Buildings and Grounds
  - Construction of B&G Building, Broussard, 1969 October 6; 2 items (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Construction of B&G Building, Broussard, 1969 November 7; 3 items (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photo- "Gift of Lee A Spencer, '13: General Buildings and Grounds", undated; 1 item (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Bryan Hall Complex
  - "The New Residence Halls at Colgate University", circa 1965-1967; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Broussard Photos, Black and White, Construction of Bryan Hall, 1966-1967; 89 items (Box 7)
  - (Box 7)
- William Colgate Memorial Hall
  Gift of James B. Colgate and named William Colgate Memorial Hall to honor his parents. Built in 1874 to house the preparatory school, Colgate Academy. When the Academy was closed in 1912, the building became the Administration Building until 1963, when the building was destroyed by a fire.
  - Photos - Students and people in front of Colgate Academy, 1873-1906; 8 (*1 stereograph) items (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Old Administration Building - negatives, 1940s-1960s; 19 and 1 glass negative items (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Colgate Academy (Exteriors), circa 1870s-1905; 10 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Old Administration Building (Exteriors), circa 1930s-1960s; 27 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Colgate Academy/Old Administration Building, undated; 4 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Old Administration Building, including Taylor Lake, circa 1915; 2 items (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Landscape views including Old Administration Building/Colgate Academy, undated; 12 items (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Records Salvage After the Fire at Colgate University", 1964; 4 items (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Administration Building Fire, 1963; 16 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Administration Buildings, Old, 1946-1873; 47 items (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Photos, Scott Phoenix, 1963; 46 items (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Negatives, Phoenix and Broussard, 1963; 21 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
- James B. Colgate
  Gift of James B. Colgate, built in 1890 to house Colgate’s Library. Edwin A. Quick was the architect of the project. In the summer of 1958, all books and library materials were moved to the new Case Library Building. The Romance language department used the space until 1964. After renovations, the James B. Colgate building became the new Administrative Building (replacing the former administration building, William Colgate Memorial Hall, which had been destroyed by a fire in 1963).
  - Exterior
    - Hill- Building of James B. Colgate, Library, 1889-1891; 3 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - James B. Colgate Exteriors, Library, 1891-1938; 4 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Moving books from James B. Colgate to New Library, 1958 Summer; 10 items (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - James B. Colgate, Library at Night, undated; 2 items (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - James B. Colgate, Administration Building, circa 1960s; 10 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - James B. Colgate Exteriors, Library, undated; 14 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - James B. Colgate Exteriors, Library (8x5 and smaller), undated; 17 items (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Stone Negatives, undated; 2 items (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Negatives, James B. Colgate, Library, 5 items (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - James B. Colgate, Library, photos mounted on cardboard, undated; 4 items (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - James B. Colgate, Library, circa 1892; 2 items (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - James B. Colgate Library and Administration Building Exteriors (Close-up), circa 1930-1963; 4 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Photos by Prof. O.B. Stanley, circa 1944-1946; 2 items (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - James B. Colgate, Exteriors, circa 1950s; 5 items (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - James B. Colgate, Administration Building, circa 1960s; 2 items (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Library - People
    - Students and Faculty Examining Books/Exhibits, circa 1940s-1950s; 34 items (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Students and Faculty at Work, circa 1940s-1950s, undated; 62 items (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Book Interiors, circa 1940s-1950s; 10 items (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Views of Books and collections, undated; 4 items (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Postcard, Bertha B. Reeves (Staff), undated; 1 item (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Negatives, circa 1940s, undated; 5 items (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Library - Interior
    - Bookstacks, undated; 23 items (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Tables and Reading Areas, undated; 12 items (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Architectural Features, undated; 11 items (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bathroom and William H. Gifford plaque, undated; 4 items (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Negatives, circa 1940s; 6 items (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Mounted Images, undated; 12 items (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Library miscellaneous
    - Photographs, various views of JCB, circa 1900 and undated; 5 items (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Typed documents, regarding History of Colgate Library, 1834-1959, 1969; 3 items (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Madisonensis Vol XXI, No 14, 1889 May 18; 1 item (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Madison University Colgate Library Dedication, 1876-1891; 20 items (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper articles regarding Colgate Library, 1894-1955; 7 items (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Booklets, Colgate Library Rules and Handbooks and related documents, 1913-1948; 57 items (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Typed documents and correspondence regarding comparison of libraries, 1926-1931; 7 items (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Reports and Valuations, 1922-1936; 27 items (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Library (Financial), 1848-1938; 25 items (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Library Forms, undated; 15 items (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Photos and documents regarding 1962 Robbery, circa 1962; 10 items (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 53 items (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Glen Falls Terra Cotta and Brick Co. v. Madison University (1890), circa 2010 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes photocopies of original court proceedings. The originals are held at the Madison County Courthouse in Wampsville, New York.
  - Administration building miscellaneous
    - Floor plan, James B. Colgate Hall, 1964 December; 6 items (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Restricted
    - Specifications for alterations and additions, James B. Colgate Administration Building, 1964 May 4; 1 item (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Everett Needham Case Library
  Built in 1959 and named after Colgate’s ninth president Edward Needham Case in 1962, the architect of the project was Robert B. O’Conner. In 1981 the building was renovated and expanded, and another major renovation project was completed in 2007.
  - Construction and Exteriors
    - Architectural Models, undated; 26 items (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Construction of Case, circa 1959; 28 items (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Ground breaking and Construction, circa 1956-1959; 53 items (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Moving Books In, Case Library, undated; 9 items (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Exterior Views, 1958-1968; 39 items (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Exterior Views, Close-up, circa 1965; 3 items (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Everett Needham Case, Dedication Plaque, 1965 April 9; 2 items (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Memorial and Honorary Designations and Floor Plans, CU Library, undated; 1 item (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Interiors and People
    - Interior Views, circa 1965-1968; 28 items (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Book stacks, circa 1962-1965; 10 items (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Interior Rooms, Rare Books, 1960-1962; 6 items (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Dog outside of Case, undated; 2 items (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - People: Reading and Studying, circa 1962-1968; 52 items (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - People: Around the Library, circa 1962-1968; 62 items (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Postcards, Interior and Exterior Case Library, 1959; 2 items (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Staff Photos, 1971; 23 items (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Library Dedication
    - "A Program for a New Library Building", 1953 November 13; 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Program: Dedication of CU Library, 1959 April 13; 3 items (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding Dedication of Case Library, 1959 March-April; 45 items (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding Dedication of Case Library, 1959 March-April; 26 items (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Regrets, Library Dedication, 1959 April; 43 items (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and photos regarding Dedication, 1959 April; 19 items (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Photos and Negatives, Library Dedication, 1959 April 13; 49 items (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Articles Re: Colgate's New Library, 1958-1959; 4 items (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Renovation and Expansion
    - News Articles regarding Library Endowment, 1976 April; 2 items (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Draft: Case for Library Renovation and Expansion", circa 1978; 5 items (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Case Library, Proposal for Renovation and Expansion, circa 1979; 2 items (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Drafts regarding Library Renovations, 1979; 21 items (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Science Library Design Guidelines, 1979 February 20; 3 items (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Library Documents, 1979-1981; 7 items (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Photos for display and descriptions, 1982 October; 9 items (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Invitation to Dedication of Charles A. Dana Addition, 1982 May 14; 1 item (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Membership, NY Library Association and 1982 Design Award, 1982, 1984; 2 items (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Case-Geyer Dedication. Recorded on Panasonic DVC, 2007 October 5; 1 item (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Colgate campus
  - Winter
    - People and views, 1918-1945; 16 items (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - People, 1958-1975; 13 items (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Outdoor views, 1950-1975; 36 items (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Campus Views
    - Campus views, 1849-1900; 15 items (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Campus views, 1910-1944; 7 items (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Campus views (Pre-Case Library, 1958), undated; 16 items (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - E.H. Stone Negatives, undated; 5 items (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Campus views, undated; 12 items (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Aerial Views
    - Aerial views, 1940, 1954; 4 items (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Aerial views, 1963-1966; 8 items (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Aerial views, undated; 20 items (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Quad
    - Buildings on the quad, 1858-1900; 17 items (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Buildings on the quad, 1906-1937; 9 items (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Quad views and buildings, undated; 8 items (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Quad views and buildings, 1953-1976, 1985; 10 items (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - E.H. Stone Negatives, undated; 12 items (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Construction of third floor, Case Library, undated; 7 items (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Olin, 1969; 1 item (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Bryan Hall, 1967; 3 items (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Alumni Hall, 1965; 2 items (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous buildings, 8 items (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Lawrence Hall, undated; 4 items (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Lathrop Link, 1970; 3 items (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Hascall Hall, 1977; 3 items (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Chapel House, undated; 4 items (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Reid Athletic Center, undated; 7 items (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Observatory, undated; 2 items (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Student Union, undated; 1 item (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Stillman, 1927, 1955, 1968; 4 items (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - East Hall, 1954; 1 item (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - West Hall, 1954; 1 item (Box 23, Folder 20)
- Colgate miscellaneous
  - Colgate's first building (Hamilton Academy, taken down in 1859), 1856, 1957; 5 items (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Building blueprints - Listing, 1950-1972; 21 items (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "New Buildings", circa 1925; 22 items (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Pencil Sketches of Campus buildings, 1969; 11 items (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds Miscellaneous, 1928-1963; 20 items (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Campus Print, 1912-1914; 18 items (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Maps of Campus, 1923-1950; 4 items (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Map of Hamilton by Philetus Spear (Includes campus), circa 1836; 1 item (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Bronze Sign Company, Inc., 1950-1951; 13 items (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Colgate Campus and its buildings, 1955, 1975, 1978; 7 items (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Names, Origins of Facility names, 1981, 1984; 30 items (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Weekly Observer article on Colgate, 1969 March 2; 4 items (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Empire magazine article on Colgate, 1969 June 1; 2 items (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Lithograph of Campus, 1892; 41 items (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Print of campus, circa 1872; 12 items (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - A.E. Sears Print of Campus, circa 1872; 12 items (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Landscaping, 1913-1964; 70 items (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Field Book - Surveying Exercise Book, 1930; 1 item (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Campus prints, 1850, 1912-1916; 7 items (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Madison University, prints, 1846; 11 items (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Madison University, prints, 1851; 3 items (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Firefighting Equipment, 1925-1926, 1944; 92 items (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Campus theorem print A, circa 1840; 10 items (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Theorem print B, circa 1840; 6 items (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Colgate University Publication, 1967 November; 2 items (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence regarding campus photos A,B,C,D, 1936 November; 3 items (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Colgate Campus, 1887, 1891; 2 items (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - View of campus, Madison University, 1870; 1 item (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Prints from negative "A", 1944; 12 items (Box 25, Folder 16)
- Campus Store (old and new)
  Completed in 1967, the O’Conner campus center and bookstore was built to replace the James C. Colgate Student Union center and the former Campus store and snackbar located in the basement of East Hall
  - Invitation to O'Connor Bookstore and Campus Center, 1967 September 5; 2 items (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Article in The College Store Journal, 1968 February-March; 4 items (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1953-1967 and undated; 26 items (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Negatives, 1954 and undated; 9 items (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Memorial Chapel
  Built in 1918. The Chapel organ was added in 1975.
  - Exterior
    - Chapel in Alumni Hall, circa 1915; 2 items (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Chapel Exteriors, circa 1920-1966; 16 items (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Chapel Exteriors and People, circa 1928-1953; 5 items (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Chapel Exteriors, circa 1984; 3 items (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Small photos (maybe cornerstone laying), 1954; 5 items (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Chapel Exteriors, undated; 22 items (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Chapel Exteriors and People, undated; 16 items (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Negatives, undated; 27 items (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - E.H. Stone Negatives, 1917, undated; 6 items (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Broussard Negatives, circa 1940-1972; 16 items (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Stone Studios, mounted on cardboard, undated; 2 items (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - O.C. Stanley photos, mounted on cardboard, 1944-1946; 5 items (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Interior and Chapel history
    - Interior Photos, undated; 20 items (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Drawings, proposed alterations to chapel, undated; 13 items (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Chapel Sketches, 1949, undated; 14 items (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Draft and Speech, Miss Mary Colgate at Chapel dedication, 1920 June; 7 items (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Chapel Organ, 1973-1975; 6 items (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Notes on the Chapel, 1914-1920; 8 items (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Chapel Specifications, 1916, undated; 2 items (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Chapel House
  Built in 1959 to provide a space for meditation, prayer, and religious study through personal experience, it is the first building of its kind on an American college campus.
  - Chapel House photographs, 1959-1971; 36 items (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Notes and brochures, Chapel House, 1959-1974; 12 items (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Meditation Center Specifications Volume 1, 1957 December 2; 1 item (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Meditation Center Specifications Volume 2, 1957 December 2; 1 item (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Colgate Cemetery
  - Articles, correspondence, documents, plot maps, 1949-1989; 101 items (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Original plots, 1973-1984; 69 items (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Clarke House
  - Notes and photographs, 1907, 1957, 1960, 1963; 5 items (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Conant House
  - Exterior photos, 1973 October; 2 items (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Cutten Complex
  - Building design and photos, 1966-1975; 14 items (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Letter of transmittal and specifications, 1964 October; 3 items (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Cooley Science Library
  - Renovations to Cooley Science Library - Project Manual, 1992 February 17; 1 item (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Cushman House
  - History, 1987 November 17; 3 items (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Dana Arts Center
  Building began in the summer of 1964 for what was a much needed space to accommodate the creative arts- art, music, performance, at Colgate. In 1979, the Eric J. Ryan Studio Center was added and named in memory of the Fine Arts instructor who passed away in 1971.
  - Paul Rudolph correspondence
    - Arts Center classroom layouts, 1965 June 30; 1 item (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Architect Paul Rudolph and proposals, 1962-1965; 238 items (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Building planning and schedule, 1963-1964; 4 items (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Proposal - Fine Arts building, 1936; 17 items (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Arts Education at Colgate, 1963-1965; 38 items (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Equipment and Furnishings, 1964-1956; 29 items (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Colgate Maroon and Sketch of Dana, 1963-1964; 3 items (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Arts Center - Development, 1962-1964; 78 items (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Job reports and inspections, 1965-1966; 35 items (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Revised plans and unbudgeted equipment and furnishings, 1964-1966; 56 items (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Leadership Campaign Kit, 1963; 1 item (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Paul Rudolph and Space needs for building, 1964-1966; 13 items (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Photographs - Construction, circa 1973; 33 items (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - Completed Interiors and Exteriors, 1974; 14 items (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Creative Arts Center,Colgate Maroon, 2 photos, 1964, 1976; 4 items (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Dana Creative Arts Center- Space Needs, 1964-1967; 30 items (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Creative Arts Center - Phase II, 1966-1967; 20 items (Box 34, Folder 3a)
  - Creative Arts Center - Phase II, 1966-1967; 47 items (Box 34, Folder 3b)
  - Creative Arts Program, 1964-1966; 24 items (Box 34, Folder 4a)
  - Creative Arts Program, 1964-1966; 28 items (Box 34, Folder 4b)
  - Arts Center Development Fund, 1962-1965; 47 items (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Ryan, Eric - Fine Arts Instructor (d. December 27, 1971), 1959-1979; 22 items (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - Interior spaces and exterior, 1966-1967, undated; 20 items (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Application for funds: Creative Arts Center and Swimming Pool, 1973 January 30; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of the Eric J. Ryan Studio, 1979 June 2; 7 items (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Paul Rudolph - Architectural Plans, 1964; 10 items (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Paul Rudolph - Architectural Plans, 1964; 18 items (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Paul Rudolph - Architectural Plans, 1964; 26 items (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - CAC Equipment - Theatre, 1966; 9 items (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - CAC Equipment - Music, 1966-1969; 49 items (Box 36, Folder 5a)
  - CAC Equipment - Music, 1966-1969; 45 items (Box 36, Folder 5b)
  - CAC Equipment - General, 1965-1967; 20 items (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Specifications - Eric Ryan Studio, 1973 March 1; 1 item (Box 37, Folder 1)
- Eaton House
  - Eaton House (Woodland Heights) - Deed, 1884 June; 4 items (Box 38, Folder 1)
- Estes House
  - Estes House-Notes and Specifications (see also postcard file), 1972, undated; 4 items (Box 38, Folder 2)
- Curtiss E. Frank Dining Hall
  - Curtiss E. Frank Dining Hall, 1988; 1 item (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Dining Hall - Frank, 1982; 61 items (Box 38, Folder 4)